Guide to the Idris Knox Papers, 1951-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Idris Knox papers 1951-1997
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Knox, Idris.
2.4 Linear Feet 276 Items
North Carolina woman who taught school in Europe.
Letters (76 items; dated 1951-1953) to parents chiefly sent from Paris with a few from Germany, describing social life and post-war atmosphere. Includes one photograph of New Year's Eve party, and telegram. Addition (200 items; dated 1976-1997) contains 42 ledgers and two loose-leaf file folders containing Knox's journals. There are also copies of the family's newsletter, and some of Knox's correspondence.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Idris Knox Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1996 and 1999.
Biographical Note
North Carolina woman who taught school in Europe.
Collection Overview
Letters (76 items; dated 1951-1953) to parents chiefly sent from Paris with a few from Germany, describing social life and post-war atmosphere. Includes one photograph of New Year's Eve party, and telegram.
Addition (200 items; dated 1976-1997) contains 42 ledgers and two loose-leaf file folders containing Knox's journals. There are also copies of the family's newsletter, and some of Knox's correspondence.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Knox, Idris
Knox family
Women travelers -- United States
College students -- Correspondence
Germany -- Social life and customs -- 20th century
Germany -- Description and travel
Diaries
Contents of Collection
- Journals, 1976-1997, (2 boxes)
  42 handwritten journals kept by Idris Knox from 1976 to 1997.
  - Journals, 1976 November-1993 May (Box 1)
  - Journals, 1993 May-1997 November (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1944-1997, (2 boxes)
  - Correspondence photocopies (Box 3)
    - Father's newsletter to family, 1944 April-1949 January
    - Outgoing personal correspondence, 1975-1997
    - Letters to parents, 1951 August-1953 August, (7 folders) (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous letters, 1951-1953
- Miscellaneous materials, 1954, (1 folder)
  - Photograph from New Year's Eve in Paris, 1954 (Box 4)